

STEFANOS SOPHOCLEOUS

Stefanos26Sophocleous@gmail.com | 559-287-2020 | Phoenix, AZ 85017 | LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/stefanos-sophocleous-736733194/

Summary

I am looking forward to using my knowledge of software development, cyber security, and networking to grow with a company to produce results as I graduate from Grand Canyon University. I am mission-oriented individual who is currently involved with the GCU Honors College, Information Technology Club, Cyber Security Club at Grand Canyon University.

Technology Experience

High-Level Languages: Java, C#, C++

Web 1.0: PHP, HTML 5, JavaScript, CSS

Front-End Framework: Angular, React JS, Spring, Bootstrap Android Studio

DataBase: MySql, PostgreSql, MongoDB Server Side Framework: Asp.Net, Node Js,

DevOps: GitHub Desktop Rest API's: Postman

Software Design Pattern: Model-View-Controller

Project Management Software: Jira

Delivery Methodologies: Scrum, Waterfall.

Development Tools: Microsoft Visual Studio, Eclipse,

Information Security: Mobile Device Security,

Virtualization, Social Engineering, Application Security Operating Systems: Linux, Windows, Kali Linux, Windows

Server 2019

Cloud Platforms: AWS, Google Cloud, Heroku, Azure,

Vmware, Virtual Box

Architecture Tools: Visio, UML, ER **Application Servers:** Tomcat, JBoss

Senior Capstone

I am in the process of creating a full stack Time and Attendance software application that gives an executive the ability to be more hands on with their HR needs. This application is a representation of my ability to follow the software development life cycle and to learn and implement new technologies with time constraints. The technologies being implemented are: Database: MongoDB, Backend Framework: Spring Boot, Frontend Framework: Angular JS

Notable Projects

Github Repository:

• https://github.com/Stefanos2021

Minesweeper Application C#.

• Description: In this application I created a Minesweeper game that implements all game rules and tracks the best score! This project implements the use of a 2D array, recursion, OOP, and the use of Windows Forms.

Note Taking Application C#

• Description: Allows a user the opportunity to validate login credentials to then create and save notes to a weekly calender. This project was done in an Agile environment where my role Backend-Developer/Project Manager. This project implements C#, JSON, and high level OOP techniques.

Android Contact Application Java

• Description: This Android studio application allows a user to create a contact, call, email, and navigate google maps. This project implements OOP, recursion, and high level understanding of data structures.

Album Store Application Spring Boot Java

• Description: In this application I worked in a CLC team to create a high level CRUD application with spring security implementing the MVC architecture. This project implements MongoDB for the database and Thymeleaf for the frontend framework.

Created Working Systems and Administration Server

• Description: Created a windows server 2019 machine from ground up to manage 3 other machines through Vmware: Windows 10, Linux, Windows 7. This project implements a high level of networking, file sharing, creation of group policies, and best security practices.

Professional Experience

DataSec | Fresno, CA Intern

05/2018 - 8/2018

Responsible for studying security software and taking ASE tests to maintain required certifications for principle partnership with Palo Alto Networks.

Provided direct supports and mental health services to adults with

AMVA Corporation | Fresno, CA **Direct Support Specialist/IT Support**

03/2021 - 08/2021

intellectual/developmental disabilities with a dual diagnosis. Supports include: providing environmental and management, structured life skill acquisition, proactive antecedent intervention. Other inquiry duties included: technology skills training, and IT support for 12+ documentation systems.

Bestbuy | Fresno, CA GeekSquad 11/2018 - 09/2019

Consultant Agent, Apple Repair Specialist and Responsible for creating service orders, shipping, receiving and communications with manufactures. Repaired hardware and software issues with clients in a high stress environment.

Education and Affiliations

Clovis West High School | Fresno, CA 2018

- Recipient of Athletic DREAM TEAM AWARD. 2018
- Eagle Character Award. 2018

Clovis Community College | Fresno CA **GED**

2019

• Member of the Principal Advisory of Student Affairs.

Grand Canyon University | Phoenix, AZ

Bachelor of Science in Software Development, Minor in Cybersecurity

Expected in 03/2022

- Enrolled in GCU Honors College
- Member of National Collegiate Scholars of Honors
- Current GPA 3.72